Guide to the Joseph Urban Papers
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series III: New York
  - Subseries III.5: Metropolitan Opera, 1917-1933
    - Le Prophète, February 7, 1918 (1928):
      - --I.1: suburb of Dordrecht, 16x21 (14x20) cm. (Box 19, Folder 2)
      - --I: City Wall in Winter, 15x25 cm. (Box 19, Folder 2)
      - --snow, Detail 9 (Box 19, Folder 2)
      - --I.2: John of Leyden's inn, 22x36 (19x32) cm. (Box B17, Folder 1)
      - --II.2: View of the City, 23x30 (17x21) cm., sig. (Box B17, Folder 2)
      - --Banquet, 19x27 (14x24) cm. (Box 19, Folder 2)
      - --Dungeon, 21x33 (19x31) cm. (Box 19, Folder 2)
      - 14 technical drawings (Box 14-9-6, Folder 2)
      - 9 photographs of costumes (Box 19, Folder 2)
      - 18 photographs of sets (Box 19, Folder 2)
      - 1 program, 1918-1919 (Box 19, Folder 2)
      - Set model
    - Oberon, December 18, 1918 (1921):
      First Metropolitan Opera performance in English of opera in 3 acts and 9 tableaux, music by Carl Maria von Weber, book by J. R. Planché, costumes by Joseph Urban, directed by Richard Ordynski, revised and conducted by Artur Bodanzky with Rosa Ponselle as Rezia, Giovanni Martinelli as Huon and Paul Althouse as Oberon.
      - 2 vocal scores, 1 inscribed by Bodanzky (Box A7, Folder 2 & 3)
      - Annotated playbook (Box 19, Folder 3)
      - 15 sketches and notes (Box 19, Folder 3)
      - 3 drawings, watercolor and pencil:
      - --Rezia's Sleeping Garden, 24x35 (20x30) cm. (Box B17, Folder 3)
      - --Storm, 24x34 (20x30) cm., sig. (Box B17, Folder 4)
      - --Charlemagne's Room, 23x33 (20x30) cm. (Box B17, Folder 5)
      - 18 technical drawings (Box 14-9-6, Folder 3)
      - 19 photographs of sets (Box 19, Folder 3)
      - 3 programs, 1918-1920 (Box 19, Folder 3)
      - Set model
        [See also Vienna, 1909-11]
    - La Juive (The Jewess), November 22, 1919 (1936):
      Opera in 5 acts by Jacques Halévy, libretto by Eugene Scribe, conducted by Artur Bodanzky with Rosa Ponselle as Rachel, Enrico Caruso as Eleazar and Leon Rothier as Cardinal Brogni.
      - 2 librettos in German (Box 19, Folder 4)
      - 4 drawings, watercolor and pencil:
      - --II.2: Passover, 22x33 (17x28) cm. (Box B17, Folder 6)
      - --III: Kaiser's garden, 24x35 (19x30) cm. (Box B17, Folder 7)
      - --IV: Cardinal's room, 24x36 (18x19) cm. (Box B17, Folder 8)
      - --V: Burning Scene, 24x35 (17x30) cm. (Box B17, Folder 9)
      - 12 technical drawings (Box 14-9-6, Folder 4)
      - 10 photographs of sets (Box 19, Folder 4)
      - Set model
    - Barbiere di Siviglia (Barber of Seville), November 27, 1919 (1951):
      Opera in 3 acts, music by Gioachino Rossini, book by Cesare Sterbini, conducted by Gennaro Papi with Giuseppe DeLuca as Figaro, Mabel Garrison as Rosina, Charles Hackett as Almaviva, Jose Mardones as Don Basilio and Pompilio Malatesta as Dr. Bartolo.
      - 1 libretto (Box 19, Folder 5)
      - 3 Drawings, watercolor and pencil:
      - --Act I: Square in Seville, 21x35 cm. (Box B17, Folder 10)
      - --Act II & III: Drawing Room, not used, 22x33 cm. (Box B17, Folder 11)
      - --Act II & III: Drawing Room, 23x37 cm. (Box B17, Folder 12)
      - 1 photograph of set drawing (Box 19, Folder 5)
      - 3 programs, 1945 - 1948 (Box 19, Folder 5)
        [See also Boston Opera 1913]
    - Parsifal, February 19, 1920 (1955):
      Opera in 3 acts and 6 scenes by Richard Wagner, English version by Henry Edward Krehbiel, costumes by Urban, conducted by Artur Bodanzky with Orville Harrold as Parsifal and Margarete Matzenauer as Kundry.
      - 1 libretto (Box 19, Folder 6)
      - 2 articles, German, 3 p. (Box B18, Folder 1)
      - 8 drawings, watercolor and pencil:
      - --Curtain, Titurel's vision (Box C4, Folder 3)
      - --I.1: Holy Woods (Box C4, Folder 4)
      - --II.1: Klingsor's tower (Box C4, Folder 5)
      - --II.2: Klingsor's garden D (Box B18, Folder 2)
      - --II.2: Klingsor's garden, unused (Box D5, Folder 1)
      - --II.2: Klingsor's garden B (Box C5, Folder 1)
      - --II.2: Klingsor's garden (Box B18, Folder 3)
      - --II.2: Klingsor's garden G (Box B18, Folder 4)
      - --II.2: Klingsor's garden (Box B31, Folder 8)
      - 2 slides from. Austrian National Library (Box 19, Folder 6)
      - 13 technical drawings (Box 14-9-6, Folder 5)
      - 17 photos of set drawings and set (Box 19, Folder 6)
      - 1 article, 1954, 6 p. (Box 19, Folder 6)
        [See also Boston, June 3, 1914.]
    - Eugene Onegin, March 24, 1920 (1921):
      The first New York performance, sung in Italian, of lyric opera in 3 acts adapted from the poem by Alexander Pushkin, music by Peter Ilich Tchaikovsky, directed by Richard Ordynski, conducted by Artur Bodanzky with Giuseppe DeLuca as Onegin, Claudia Muzio as Tatiana and Giovanni Martinelli as Lenski.
      - Libretto (Box 19, Folder 7)
      - 4 drawings, watercolor and pencil:
      - --Act I: Larina's garden, 43x25 (20.5x37) cm. (Box D5, Folder 2)
      - --Act 1.3: garden B, 26x36 (16x26) cm. (Box B18, Folder 5)
      - --Act II: Larina's ballroom, 26x36 (17x26) cm. (Box B18, Folder 6)
      - --Act II.2: Duel, 25x35 (16x26) cm. (Box B18, Folder 7)
      - 3 technical drawings (Box 14-9-6, Folder 6)
      - 10 photographs of set drawings (Box 19, Folder 7)
      - Program, April 1, 1920 (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - Tristan und Isolde, November 20, 1920 (1958):
      Performed in English, by Richard Wagner, conducted by Artur Bodanzky, with Johannes Sembach as Tristan, Margarete Matzenauer as Isolde, and Clarence Whitehill as Kurvenal.
      - 2 drawings, watercolor and pencil, sig.:
      - --II: King Mark's Castle, 24x33 (20x30) cm. (Box B18, Folder 8)
      - --III: Tristan's Courtyard, 24x32 (20x30) cm. (Box B18, Folder 9)
      - Rough sketch (Box 19, Folder 8)
      - 9 technical drawings (Box 14-9-6, Folder 7)
      - Photograph of set drawing (Box 19, Folder 8)
      - 5 programs 1935-55 (Box 19, Folder 8)
      - Set models
        [See also Boston Opera 1912 and Interstate Opera, 1916]
    - Don Carlos, December 23, 1920 (1923):
      First Metropolitan performance of opera based on tragedy by Schiller, music by Giuseppe Verdi, libretto by Mery and Camille du Locle, costumes by Gretl Urban, conducted by Gennaro Papi with Giovanni Martinelli as Don Carlos, Giuseppe DeLuca as Rodrigo, Adamo Didur as Phillip, and Rosa Ponselle as Elizabeth.
      - 7 drawings, watercolor and pencil:
      - --I: Wood scene, 23x31 cm. (Box B18, Folder 10)
      - --II: Church, 26x38 cm. (Box B18, Folder 11)
      - --III.1: Ballet scene, 26x38 cm. (Box B18, Folder 12)
      - --Grotto scene, 22x31 cm. (Box B18, Folder 13)
      - --III.2: City Square, 26x38 cm. (Box B19, Folder 1)
      - --IV.1: King's cabinet, Phillip's room, 23x31 cm. (Box B19, Folder 2)
      - --IV.2: Prison scene, 23x30 cm. (Box B19, Folder 3)
      - 8 technical drawings (Box 14-9-6, Folder 8)
      - 17 photographs of set drawings (Box 20, Folder 1)
      - Set model, Convent exterior
    - Lohengrin, February 2, 1921 (1950):
      Opera in 3 acts and 4 scenes by Richard Wagner, performed in English, costumes by Joseph and Gretl Urban, conducted by Artur Bodanzky with Johannes Sembach as Lohengrin and Florence Easton as Elsa.
      - 1 libretto, German (Box 20, Folder 2)
      - 4 drawings, watercolor and pencil:
      - --Act I: River bank, 17x28 (13x23) cm., sig. (Box 20, Folder 2)
      - --Act II: Courtyard, 18x28 (13x23) cm., sig. (Box 20, Folder 2)
      - --2 of Act III.1: Bedroom (Box 20, Folder 2)
      - 6 technical drawings (Box 14-9-6, Folder 9)
      - 8 photographs of sets (Box 20, Folder 2)
      - 5 programs, 1937-1950 (Box 20, Folder 2)
      - Set models
        [See also Vienna 1909-11]
    - La Traviata, November 14, 1921 (1935):
      Opera in 4 acts, music by Giuseppe Verdi, book by F. M. Piave, conducted by Roberto Moranzoni with Amelita Galli-Curci as Violetta, Beniamino Gigli as Alfredo, and Giuseppe De Luca as Germont.
      - 1 drawing, watercolor and pencil:
      - --Flora's Palace, 25x32 (15x18) cm. (Box B19, Folder 4)
      - 3 plans & sketches (Box 20, Folder 3)
      - 5 technical drawings (Box 14-9-6, Folder 10)
      - 7 photographs of set drawings (Box 20, Folder 3)
      - Program, 4/1/32 (Box 20, Folder 3)
      - Set models
        [See also Boston Opera, December 21, 1912]
    - Ernani, December 8, 1921 (1929):
      Opera in 4 acts and 5 scenes, music by Giuseppe Verdi, book by F. M. Piave based on Hernani by Victor Hugo, costumes by Gretl Urban, conducted by Gennaro Papi with Giovanni Martinelli as Ernani, Giuseppe Danise as Don Carlos and Rosa Ponselle as Elvira.
      - 2 librettos (Box 20, Folder 4)
      - 7 drawings-watercolor and pencil, 16x26 (10x16) cm.:
      - --Act I.1: first idea, sig. (Box 20, Folder 4)
      - --Act I.1: Sea, stone bridge (Box 20, Folder 4)
      - --Act II: Elvira's Room, sig. (Box 20, Folder 4)
      - --Act III.1: Throne Room A (Box 20, Folder 4)
      - --Act III.1: Throne Room B, sig. (Box 20, Folder 4)
      - --Act III.2: Tomb Scene A, sig. (Box 20, Folder 4)
      - --Act III.2: Tomb Scene B (Box 20, Folder 4)
      - 9 technical drawings (Box 14-9-6, Folder 11)
      - 6 photographs (Box 20, Folder 4)
      - 1 program, 1922-1923 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Salzburg Festival Playhouse Fund, 1921-1922:
      Richard Strauss, while on a US tour in the fall of 1921, enlisted the aid of Mrs. Samuel(Minnie) Untermeyer to raise money for the Salzburg Festival. Strauss, with Max Reinhardt and Hugo von Hofmannstal, had formed the Salzburg Festspielhaus Committee whose purpose was to build a theater dedicated to Mozart in war-devastated Austria.
      - 5 letters, 10 p. (Box 20, Folder 5)
      - 1 flyer (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Le Roi d'Ys, January 5, 1922:
      First New York performance of opera in 3 acts and 5 scenes, music by Edouard Lalo, book by Edouard Blau, costumes by Gretl Urban, directed by Samuel Thewman, conducted by Albert Wolff with Beniamino Gigli as Mylio, Giuseppe Danise as Karnac, Leon Rothier as the King, Rosa Ponselle as Margared and Frances Alda as Rozenn.
      - 8 drawings, watercolor and pencil on board:
      - --Act I & II, 26x16 (10x15) cm. (Box 20, Folder 6)
      - --Act II, 2:Grotto and set notes, 16x26 (10x14) (Box 20, Folder 6)
      - --Act III: Courtyard, Flood, 26x16 (10x15) cm. (Box 20, Folder 6)
      - --Act I: Castle, 15.5x26 (10x16) cm. (Box 20, Folder 6)
      - --Act II.1: Interior, 16x26 (10x16) cm (Box 20, Folder 6)
      - --Act II.2: Grotto, 16x26 (10x16) cm. (Box 20, Folder 6)
      - --III.1: Courtyard, 16x26 (10x16) cm. (Box 20, Folder 6)
      - --III.2: Flood, 16x26 (10x16) cm. (Box 20, Folder 6)
      - 5 technical drawings (Box 14-9-6, Folder 12)
      - 11 photographs of set drawings (Box 20, Folder 6)
      - 2 programs, 1921-22 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Cosi Fan Tutte, March 24, 1922 (1928):
      First New York performance of the opera buffa in 2 acts, music by Wolfgang Amadeus Mozart, book by Lorenzo da Ponte, costumes by Gretl Urban, directed by Samuel Thewman, conducted by Artur Bodanzky with Florence Easton as Fiordiligi, Frances Peralta as Dorabella, George Meader as Ferrando, Giuseppe DeLuca as Guglielmo, Adamo Didur as Don Alfonso and Lucrezia Bori as Despina.
      - 5 drawings, watercolor and pencil:
      - --Act I.1: Inn, 36x43 (20x29) cm. (Box B19, Folder 5)
      - --Act I.2,4; II.2: Garden, 27x35 (19x26) cm. (Box B19, Folder 6)
      - --Act I.3: Green Room, 27x35 (19x26) cm. (Box B19, Folder 7)
      - --Act II.1: White Room, 27x35 (19x27) cm. (Box B19, Folder 8)
      - --Act II.3: Tapestry Room, 27x35 (19x27) cm. (Box B19, Folder 9)
      - 5 technical drawings (Box 14-9-6, Folder 13)
      - Set list (Box 20, Folder 7)
      - 6 photographs of set drawings (Box 20, Folder 7)
      - 2 programs, 1921-22 (Box 20, Folder 7)
      - Set model-Portal
    - Madama Butterfly, November 24, 1922:
      Tragic opera in 3 acts, music by Giacomo Puccini, lyrics by L. Illica & G. Giacosa from the book by John L. Long and play by David Belasco, conducted by Roberto Moranzoni with Florence Easton as Cio-Cio-San, Giovanni Martinelli as Pinkerton and Antonio Scotti as Sharpless.
      - 1 libretto (Box 21, Folder 1)
      - 1 drawing-watercolor and pencil:
      - --Act II, III: Cio-Cio-San's House, 21x30 (16x24) cm. (Box 21, Folder 1)
      - 5 technical drawings, sketchesm. (Box 21, Folder 1)
      - 4 technical drawings (Box 14-9-6, Folder 14)
      - 8 programs, 1945-1953 (Box 21, Folder 1)
      - 1 set model-Act I, Border #1
        [See also Boston Opera November 29, 1912 ]
    - Roméo et Juliette, November 25, 1922 (1947):
      Opera in 5 acts and 7 scenes, music by Charles Gounod, book by Jules Barbier and Michel Carré, costumes by Gretl Urban, conducted by Louis Hasselmans with Lucrezia Bori as Juliette, Beniamino Gigli as Roméo, Giuseppe DeLuca as Mercutio and Leon Rothier as Friar Laurence.
      - 1 libretto (Box 21, Folder 2)
      - 6 drawings, watercolor and pencil:
      - --Prologue, 21x31 (15x24) cm. (Box B19, Folder 10)
      - --Ballroom, 21x31 (15x24) cm. (Box B19, Folder 11)
      - --Garden scene, not used, 21x31 (16x24) cm. (Box B19, Folder 12)
      - --Square, 21x31 (15x24) cm. (Box B19, Folder 13)
      - --Bedroom, 21x31 (15x24) cm. (Box B20, Folder 1)
      - --Tomb 21x31 (15x24) cm. (Box B20, Folder 2)
      - Ground plans, 1 p. (Box 21, Folder 2)
      - 8 technical drawings (Box 14-9-6, Folder 15)
      - 2 photographs of set drawing (Box 21, Folder 2)
      - 2 programs, 1922-23, 1926-27 (Box 21, Folder 2)
      - Set model
    - Thaïs, December 14, 1922 (1939):
      Opera by Jules Massenet, libretto by Louis Gallet, costumes by Gretl Urban, conducted by Louis Hasselmans with Maria Jeritza as Thaïs, Orville Harrold as Nicias and Clarence Whitehill as Athanael.
      - 3 sketches & notes (Box 21, Folder 3)
      - 8 technical drawings (Box 14-9-6, Folder 16)
      - Set model
        [See also Boston Opera, December 7, 1912]
    - Concert Sets, 1922, 1929:
      - Detail, measurements (Box 21, Folder 4)
      - 6 technical drawings, 58x77 cm. (Box 14-9-6, Folder 17)
    - L'Africaine, March 21, 1923 (1934):
      Opera in four acts and 5 scenes, music by Giacomo Meyerbeer, book by Eugene Scribe, costumes by Gretl Urban, directed by Samuel Thewman, conducted by Artur Bodanzky with Beniamino Gigli as Vasco Da Gama, Rosa Ponselle as Selika and Giuseppe Danise as Nelusko, Adamo Didur as Don Pedro and Leon Rothier as the Grand Inquisitor.
      - 2 librettos (Box 21, Folder 5)
      - 2 drawings, watercolor and pencil:
      - --1. Court Room, 20.5x30.7 cm. (Box 21, Folder 5)
      - --IV. 2: Promontory, 17.5x18.5 cm. (Box 21, Folder 5)
      - 5 p. sketches of ship, Act III (Box 14-9-7, Folder 1)
      - 8 technical drawings (Box 21, Folder 5)
      - 1 program (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - L'Amico Fritz, November 15, 1923 (1924):
      Comedy in 3 acts by Pietro Mascagni, conducted by Roberto Moranzoni with Lucrezia Bori as Suzel and Miguel Fleta as Fritz, and Giuseppe Danise as Rabbi David.
      - Libretto (Box 21, Folder 6)
      - 4 Drawings, watercolor and pencil:
      - --Dining Room (not used), 26x44 (19x36) cm. (Box B20, Folder 3)
      - --Dining Room B, 28x36 (16x23) cm. (Box B20, Folder 4)
      - --Terrace A, 28x46 (36x19) cm. (Box B20, Folder 5)
      - --Terrace, used, 24x31 (15x23) cm. (Box B20, Folder 6)
      - 4 ground plans (Box 14-9-7, Folder 2)
    - Carmen, November 22, 1923 (1950):
      Opera in 4 acts with music by Georges Bizet, lyrics by H. Meilhac & L. Halévy based on the novel by Prosper Merimée, costumes by Gretl Urban, conducted by Louis Hasselmans with Florence Easton as Carmen and Giovanni Martinelli as Jose.
      - 2 librettos (Box 21, Folder 7)
      - 4 drawings, watercolor and pencil:
      - --Act I: Square in Seville, 23x30 (16x23) cm., sig. (Box B20, Folder 7)
      - --Act II: Tavern, 23x30 (16x23) cm. (Box B20, Folder 8)
      - --Act III: Smuggler scene, 23x30 (16x23) cm., sig. (Box B20, Folder 9)
      - --Act IV: Arma scene, 23x30 (12x20) cm. (Box B20, Folder 10)
      - 4 technical drawings (Box 14-9-7, Folder 3)
      - 5 photographs of set drawings (Box 21, Folder 7)
      - 4 programs, 1937-1950 (Box 21, Folder 7)
        [See also Boston Opera, January 15, 1913]
    - Faust, November 30, 1923 (1951):
      A new design for the prolog was added to the 1917 production. Conducted by Louis Hasselmans with Giovanni Martinelli as Faust, Lawrence Tibbett as Valentin, Fiodr Chaliapin as Mephistopheles and Frances Alda as Margarette.
      - 1 drawing, watercolor and pencil:
      - --Study, 22x33 (14x23) cm. (Box 21, Folder 8)
      - 1 ground plan (Box 14-9-7, Folder 4)
      - 3 programs, 1942-50 (Box 21, Folder 8)
        [See also Vienna 1906, Boston 1913 and Metropolitan Opera November 25, 1917 ]
    - Fedora, December 8, 1923 (1926):
      A lyric drama in 3 acts, music by Umberto Giordano, book by V. Sardou, directed by Wilhelm von Wymetal, conducted by Gennaro Papi, with Maria Jeritza as Fedora, Giovanni Martinelli as Loris Ipanov and Antonio Scotti as De Siriex.
      - 1 libretto (Box 21, Folder 9)
      - 4 p. of script notes, von Wymetal (Box 21, Folder 9)
      - 2 drawings-watercolor and pencil:
      - --Drawing room, 22x30.5 (16x25) cm. (Box 21., Folder 9)
      - --Bed room, 22.5x31.5 (16x25) cm., sig. (Box 21, Folder 9)
      - 1 set sketch (Box 21, Folder 9)
      - 5 technical drawings (Box 14-9-7, Folder 5)
    - Martha, December 14, 1923 (1929):
      Opera by Friedrich von Flotow, conducted by Gennaro Papi with Frances Alda as Harriet, Kathleen Howard as Nancy, Beniamino Gigli as Lionel and Giuseppe DeLuca as Plunkett.
      - 2 drawings, watercolor and/or pencil:
      - --I: Village square, 28x38 (15x22) cm. (Box B20, Folder 11)
      - --Kitchen scene, 22x29 (15x23) cm. (Box 21, Folder 10)
      - 2 sketches (Box 21, Folder 10)
      - 5 technical drawings (Box 14-9-7, Folder 6)
        [See also Boston March 24, 1913.]
    - Freischütz, Der, March 22, 1924 (1929):
      Opera in 3 acts, music by Carl Maria von Weber, libretto by Friedrich Kind, conducted by Artur Bodanzky with Elizabeth Rethberg as Agathe, Curt Taucher as Max, Michael Bohnen as Caspar and Leon Rothier as the hermit.
      - 1 libretto (Box 21, Folder 11)
      - 4 p. of script notes (Box 21, Folder 11)
      - 3 drawings-watercolor and pencil:
      - --II.1: Hunter's room, 22x31 (14x22) cm. (Box 21, Folder 11)
      - --II.2: Wolves Glen, 34x38 (30x34) cm. (Box C5, Folder 2)
      - --II.2: Wolves Glen B, 28x38 (23x34) cm. (Box B21, Folder 1)
      - 1 sketch (Box 21, Folder 11)
      - 8 technical drawings (Box 14-9-.7, Folder 7)
      - 1 program, 1928-1929 (Box 21, Folder 11)
      - Set model
        [See Vienna undated]
    - Contes d'Hoffman, (Tales of Hoffman), November 13, 1924 (1946):
      Comic opera in 4 acts, music by Jacques Offenbach, book by Jules Barbier, conducted by Louis Hasselmans with Nina Morgana as Olympia, Lucrezia Bori as Giulietta and Antonia, Giuseppe DeLuca as Coppelius, Miguel Fleta as Hoffman and Lawrence Tibbett as Schlemil.
      - Libretto (Box 21, Folder 12)
      - 5 drawings, watercolor and pencil, sig.:
      - --I: Prologue-Tavern, 27x35 (16x24) cm. (Box B21, Folder 2)
      - --II: a. Olympia-Physician's room, 27x34 (16x24) cm. (Box B21, Folder 3)
      - --II: b. Olympia-ballroom, 27x34 (16x24) cm. (Box B21, Folder 4)
      - --III: Giulietta, 27x34 (16x24) cm. (Box B21, Folder 5)
      - --IV: Antonia, 27x34 (16x24) cm. (Box B21, Folder 6)
      - 1 p. set notes (Box 21, Folder 12)
      - 3 detail drawings (Box 21, Folder 12)
      - 8 technical drawings (Box 14-9-7, Folder 8)
      - 7 photographs of set drawings (Box 21, Folder 12)
        [See also Boston Opera, November 25, 1912]
    - Falstaff, January 2, 1925 (1949):
      Opera based on The Merry Wives of Windsor by Shakespeare, music by Giuseppe Verdi, libretto by Arrigo Boito, costumes by Gretl Urban, directed by Wilhelm von Wymetal, conducted by Tullio Serafin with Antonio Scotti as Falstaff, Frances Alda as Anne, Lawrence Tibbett as Ford, Lucrezia Bori as Mistress Ford and Adamo Didur as Pistol.
      - Libretto (Box 21, Folder 13)
      - 3 photographs of sets (Box 21, Folder 13)
      - 2 p. script notes (Box 21, Folder 13)
      - 1 set sketch and notes (Box 21, Folder 13)
      - 2 drawings, watercolor and pencil:
      - --Portal detail (Box 21, Folder 13)
      - --Ford's room, 27x34.5 (16x24) cm. (Box B21, Folder 7)
      - 5 technical drawings (Box 14-9-7, Folder 9)
      - 2 photographs of set drawings (Box 21, Folder 13)
    - Pelléas et Mélisande, March 21, 1925 (1949):
      First Metropolitan performance of opera in 5 acts by Claude Debussy, adapted from the play by Maurice Maeterlinck, costumes by Gretl Urban, conducted by Louis Hasselmans with Clarence Whitehill as Golaud, Leon Rothier as Arkel, Lucrezia Bori as Mélisande and Edward Johnson as Pelléas.
      - 2 librettos (Box 22, Folder 1)
      - 1 set sketch (Box 22, Folder 1)
      - 5 technical drawings (Box B21, Folder 8)
      - 13 photos of set drawings (Box 22, Folder 1)
      - Set model
        [See also Boston January 10, 1912.]
    - Der Barbier von Bagdad (Barber of Bagdad), November 7, 1925 (1926):
      Opera in 2 acts, book and music by Peter Cornelius, directed by Samuel Thewman, conducted by Artur Bodanzky with George Meader as Kadi Baba Mustapha and Elisabeth Rethberg as Margiana.
      - Libretto, German (Box 22, Folder 2)
      - Rough sketch, pencil (Box B21, Folder 9)
      - 2 Drawings-watercolor and pencil, sig.:
      - --Act I: Room, Nueddin's House, 27x35 cm. (Box B21, Folder 9)
      - --Act II: Mustapha's women's room, 27x35 cm. (Box B21, Folder 10)
      - 7 technical drawings (Box 22, Folder 2)
      - 8 technical drawings (Box 14-9-7, Folder 10)
      - 1 photograph of Act I set (Box 22, Folder 2)
      - 1 program, 1925-1926 (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - La Vestale, November 12, 1925 (1927):
      First Metropolitan performance of opera in 3 acts by Gaspare Spontini, book by De Jouy, costumes by Gretl Urban, directed by Wilhelm Von Wymetal, conducted by Tullio Serafin with Rosa Ponselle as Giulia, Edward Johnson as Licinio, Giuseppe De Luca as Cinna and Margarete Matzenauer as the High Priestess.
      - 5 drawings, watercolor and pencil on board:
      - --I: Forum, 26x33 (22x33) cm., sig. (Box B21, Folder 11)
      - --II: Vestal Temple, 21x45 (21x32) cm. (Box B22, Folder 1)
      - --III.1: Campus Sceleratus, 32x45 (23x33) cm., sig. (Box B22, Folder 2)
      - --III.1: Cemetary (Box 22, Folder 3)
      - --III.2: Arena, 32x45 (22x33), sig. (Box B22, Folder 3)
      - 6 technical drawings (Box 22, Folder 3)
      - 24 technical drawings (Box 14-9-7, Folder 11)
      - 5 photos of set drawings (Box 22, Folder 3)
      - 2 programs 1925-26 (Box 22, Folder 3)
      - Set models
    - Cena delle Beffe, January 2, 1926 (1927):
      First Metropolitan performance of opera by Umberto Giordano based on the play The Jest by Sem Benelli, conducted by Tullio Serafin with Beniamino Gigli as Gianetto Malaspini, Frances Alda as Ginevra, Titta Ruffo as Neri and Adamo Didur as the Doctor.
      - 3 drawings, watercolor and pencil, sig.:
      - --Act 1: Banquet Hall, 19x19 (10x15) cm. (Box 22, Folder 4)
      - --Act II, IV, bedroom, 19x19 (9x14) cm. (Box 22, Folder 4)
      - --Act III: Prison, 19x19 (19x15) cm. (Box 22, Folder 4)
      - 4 technical drawings (Box D5, Folder 3)
      - 6 sketches on tracing paper (Box 22, Folder 4)
      - 4 photographs of set drawings (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - La Vida Breve, March 6, 1926.:
      First American performance of opera by Manuel de Falla, costumes by Gretl Urban, conducted by Tullio Serafin with Lucrezia Bori as Salud.
      - 3 drawings, watercolor and pencil: